Guide to the Meredith Tax papers, 1956-2016 RL.01275
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Meredith Tax papers
1956-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Tax, Meredith
RL.01275
125 Linear Feet 213 boxes
Meredith Tax is a feminist writer and organizer who has been active since the 1960s. This large collection of her papers includes many files of records documenting her activism in feminism and her role in founding feminist organizations; drafts and manuscripts of her writings, music, and art; personal and professional correspondence; research materials; and subject files. Organizations well represented include Bread and Roses; Women's WORLD; CARASA (Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse); PEN American Center Women's Committee; and the International PEN Women's Writers Committee, as well as many other materials on other organizations. There are also 89 audio cassettes and a few VHS tapes and optical media containing Tax's research interviews as well as interviews with Tax. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture at Duke University.
Biographical Note
Meredith Tax was born in Wisconsin on September 18, 1942. She was educated in the Milwaukee public school system and at Brandeis University, where she graduated magna cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa and with Woodrow Wilson and Fulbright fellowships. She then studied at the University of London where she became involved in the anti-war movement. Returning to the U.S. in 1968, she continued her anti-war activism and was one of the founding members of Boston's Bread and Roses collective, a socialist feminist group.
Her essay, Woman and Her Mind: The Story of Daily Life, (1970) is often considered a founding document of the woman's movement and is one of the first texts to discuss sexual harassment. Then moving to Chicago, she worked in factories and as a nurses aide and continued her activism in the Chicago Women's Liberation Union.
In 1976, she moved to New York, and was founding cochair of the Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA), which helped start the Reproductive Rights National Network, of which she was a steering committee member. She also was a parent initiator of an alternative public elementary school in District 3 in New York.
Tax's writings include a history book, The Rising of the Women: Feminist Solidarity and Class Conflict (1980), two historical novels, Rivington Street (1982) and Union Square (1988), and a children's picture book, Families (1981).
In 1986, Tax and Grace Paley initiated the PEN American Center Women's Committee and became its co-chairs; she later became founding Chair of International PEN's Women Writers' Committee and, in 1994, was founding President of Women's WORLD, a global free speech network that fights gender-based censorship.
This biographical note was created in part from information provided on Tax's website, meredithtax.org
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access note
Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Use copies of the audiocassette material in boxes 205-207 are available on reading room workstation.
Provenance
The Meredith Tax papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as purchases and gifts in 2010, 2011, 2012, and 2017.
Collection Overview
The Meredith Tax papers include materials from the activist organizations she was involved with, as well as drafts and manuscripts of her written work, some personal correspondence, teaching materials, and audio/visual materials.
The largest group of materials at over 130 boxes documents Tax's long career as an activist, beginning with her involvement in Boston's Bread and Roses, a socialist-feminist collective through her continued work with Women's WORLD, a global free speech network Tax cofounded in 1994 to fight gender-based censorship. Other organizations Tax was involved in are also well documented in the collection, including CARASA (Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse); PEN American Center Women's Committee; and International PEN Women's Writers Committee. Smaller amounts of material come from Tax's work with the October League, Chicago Women's Liberation Union, National Writers' Union, and the West Side Community School, as well as other organizations. These materials include committee and board materials, events files, conferences, and many files of organizational notes and records.
Tax's work as a writer, including books, both fiction and nonfiction, articles, essays, and speeches as well as songs, is represented in the Writings, Speeches, and Songs series. The Correspondence series includes both personal and professional correspondence. The Subject Files were created by Tax for research related to her activism and her writing.
Finally, there are 89 audiocassettes, 53 of which contain Tax's research interviews and 36 of which contain interviews with Tax, readings by Tax and board meetings. Other interviews are on several VHS videocassettes and optical discs.
Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture at Duke University.
Abortion -- Political aspects; Abortion -- United States; Feminist music -- United States; Feminism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Feminists -- New York (State) -- New York; Reproductive rights and policy; Reproductive rights -- United States; Women authors; Women political activists; Women's rights -- United States; Audiocassettes; Optical disks; Videocassettes; Chicago Women's Liberation Union; Bread & Roses (Organization); October League (M-L); Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (New York, N.Y.); PEN (Organization); PEN (Organization) -- Women Writers Committee; Tax, Meredith -- Rivington Street; Tax, Meredith -- Union Square; Tax, Meredith -- Rising of the Women; Women's WORLD; Tax, Meredith; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Organizational Materials, 1958-2013; 130 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Series contains materials relating to the various activist organizations Meredith Tax has been a part of beginning in the 1960s through the first decade of the twentieth century. Those with the most extensive documentation are Bread and Roses, a Boston based socialist-feminist organization; CARASA (Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse); PEN American Center Women's Committee; International PEN Women's Writers Committee; and Women's WORLD. Other organizations Tax was a part of and are documented in this series include the October League; the Chicago Women's Liberation Union; National Writers Union; the West Side Community School; and the Center for Secular Space (CSS), the INGO founded by Tax.
  The records in this series documents the activities, both internal and external, of these organizations and include executive board and committee records, program files, reports, conference files, correspondence, information on grants and fundraising activities, and research files related to the organizations' missions. Tax's original folder titles have been retained where possible.
  Tax was a founding member of many of these organizations, so material from the inception of these organizations is often included. Tax's work with both PEN American and International PEN focuses on gender-based censorship, and Women's WORLD is an organization she cofounded to continue that work at a global level.
  - Women's Liberation: Boston pre-Bread and Roses, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Bread and Roses (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Notes ch. 5 Bread and Roses (Box 1)
  - GE Strike (Box 1)
  - Women's Liberation: Bread and Roses position papers and general - also notes (Box 1)
  - Women's Liberation: Bread and Roses study group summer 1970 (Box 1)
  - Women's Liberation: Boston 1971 and after (Box 1)
  - Bread and Roses Internal papers (Box 1)
  - Collective Bread and Roses (Box 1)
  - Women's Liberation: Bread and Roses Women's Health Center (Box 1)
  - Ginny Harpur (Box 1)
  - Bread and Roses Newsletter (Box 1)
  - Bread and Roses lists (Box 1)
  - Chicago Women's Liberation Union (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - International Women's Day, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA) (Box 3-7)
  - CARASA (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - CARASA News (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - CARASA News (Box 9)
  - CARASA (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Reproductive Rights National Network (Box 9)
  - CARASA (Box 10)
  - CARASA: Lit. and Prop. (Box 10)
  - CARASA Steering Committee (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - March 31, NYC (Box 10)
  - CARASA demonstrations (Box 10)
  - CARASA correspondence, local (Box 10)
  - CARASA Conference, 1979 (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - CARASA historical documents (Box 10)
  - CARASA historical materials (Box 11)
  - Feminist Emergency Action Group (Box 11)
  - CARASA Legislative Committee (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Clippings (Box 11)
  - National Committee (Box 11)
  - CARASA Buffalo, state meetings, etc. (Box 11)
  - CARASA, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Boston - AAL, etc. (Box 11)
  - Committee to End Sterilization Abuse, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Sterilization (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Sterilization, 1979 (Box 12)
  - R2N2 (Box 12)
  - Chicago Reproductive Rights Network/NAM (Box 12)
  - Regional (Box 12)
  - Correspondence (Box 12)
  - Fall mobilization, national coalition, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Research and Notes, CARASA, etc. (Box 12)
  - Right to lifers (Box 12)
  - Right Wing (Box 12)
  - ICAR (Box 13)
  - LIPA Conference, Boston, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Marxist Education Collective (Box 13)
  - NAM and reproductive rights (Box 13)
  - Native American Solidarity Committee (Box 13)
  - NY State campaign abortion rights (Box 13)
  - Catholic alternatives (Box 13)
  - CDRR (Box 13)
  - CCROW, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Family planning advocates (Box 13)
  - Feminist Health Works (Box 13)
  - Healthright, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Sterilization abuse: organizer's packet, CARASA, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Anti-repression (Box 13)
  - Right wing/New right (Box 13)
  - Ad hoc committee on Sterilization abuse (Box 13)
  - In These Times/Abortion, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Population control (Box 13)
  - CARASA (Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse) Abortion Rights Action Week, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - CARASA administrative files, 5 folders (Box 14)
  - CARASA events (Box 14)
  - CARASA newsletters (Box 14)
  - CARASA notes for speeches (Box 14)
  - CARASA speeches (Box 14)
  - CARASA reports (Box 14)
  - International Women's Day, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Simone de Beauvoir conference, 1979 September (Box 14)
  - Barnard "Sex Conference" protest, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Freedom to Write (Box 15)
  - PEN American (4 folders) (Box 15)
  - Reconstruction Committee, 1991 (Box 15)
  - PEN Foundation papers, 1990-1991 (Box 15)
  - PEN - my work (newsletters) (Box 15)
  - Board Minutes and materials (Box 15)
  - PEN Bylaws revision, 1986-1987 (Box 15)
  - PEN Annual Reports (Box 15)
  - PEN Membership Lists (Box 15)
  - International PEN Reform correspondence (Box 15)
  - PEN American Center fundraising (Box 15)
  - PEN events, 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - Freedom to Write (Box 16)
  - Tax Reform Act, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Events, 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - PEN Admissions Committee (Box 16)
  - Adventures of a PEN Gatecrasher by Mary Duncan (Box 16)
  - PEN American Center Board, 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - PEN American (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - PEN American Planning Committee, 1988-1989 (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - PEN American (6 folders) (Box 17)
  - PEN American (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - Karen Kannerly (Box 18)
  - Members Council, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Freedom to Write, 1991-1992 (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - South Africa Boycott (Box 19)
  - PEN American (4 folders) (Box 19)
  - Nominating Committee, 1991 (Box 20)
  - PEN American Center, 1994 (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - Coalition opposed to censorship in the arts (Box 20)
  - Mapplethorpe flak in DC, 1989 (Box 20)
  - PEN American (Box 20)
  - Taboos speech to PEN Women's Committee, 1992 (Box 21)
  - Freedom to Write (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Women's Committee (Box 21)
  - PEN American (3 folders) (Box 21)
  - PEN American Executive Board (Box 22)
  - PEN American (Box 23)
  - Women's Committee Lists, 1986 (Box 24)
  - PEN Women's Committee Steering Committee (Box 24)
  - Women's Committee (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Correspondence (Box 24)
  - Organizing Group for International Women's Committee (Box 24)
  - PEN American (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Plans for program on censorship and reproductive rights, 1989 (Box 25)
  - PEN/Censorship and WC 1986 (Box 25)
  - Literary relationships among women, 1987 (Box 25)
  - Central American Women Poets for Peace, reception and reading (Box 25)
  - PEN Women's Committee minutes and agendas (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, PEN/WC, 1986 (Box 25)
  - PEN General Meeting/Election, 1986 (Box 25)
  - PEN International Congress, Women's protest and petition, 1986 (Box 25)
  - PEN Women's Committee, 1989-1991 (3 folders) (Box 26)
  - Readings: Our Bodies, Our Books (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 26)
  - PEN International Congress, 1986 (2 folders) (Box 26)
  - PEN Newsletter on Congress, my article (Box 26)
  - Clippings (Box 27)
  - Membership (Box 27)
  - PEN American Freedom to Write committee (3 folders) (Box 27)
  - PEN American Center, 2000-2004 (3 folders) (Box 27)
  - PEN American Center Emergency Fund application (Box 27)
  - PEN American Center Newsletters (Box 27)
  - Cindy Cisler (Box 27)
  - US Domestic Censorship Feminists for Free Expression, 1992 (Box 28)
  - Reproductive Rights Reading (Box 28)
  - PEN Women's Committee, 1988-1989 (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - PEN West (Box 28)
  - Grace Paley/War Resisters League, 1987 (Box 28)
  - Community outreach (Box 28)
  - WC Reproductive Rights/Censorship Event/Notes (Box 28)
  - PEN American Center, 2006 (2 folders) (Box 29)
  - PEN Literary Festival, 2006 (2 folders) (Box 29)
  - First International Women Writers Conference, Paris, 1989 (3 folders) (Box 30)
  - Carol Pratt/Sphinx etc., 1989 (Box 30)
  - France (Box 30)
  - Int. Assoc. des femmes écrivains, 1989 (Box 30)
  - IREX grants for Prague (Box 31)
  - US Mail re Int. W.C., 1991-1992 (Box 31)
  - My W.C. mailings re: Croatia (Box 31)
  - Gender-Based Censorship: Another Human Rights Abuse (Box 31)
  - Ama Event, 1993 (Box 31)
  - PIP Grant/Publishing workshop (Box 31)
  - PEN - Internet Info (Box 31)
  - IPWWC, 1997 (Box 31)
  - Current expenses PEN/WW (Box 31)
  - International Mailing, 1992 (Box 31)
  - Brochures (Box 31)
  - French program (Box 31)
  - Pre-Congress mailing, 1993 (Box 31)
  - International PEN (4 folders) (Box 31)
  - 5 Witches Pamphlet (Box 32)
  - IPWWC (Box 32)
  - Network: Newsletter of the International PEN Women Writers Committee (Box 32)
  - International PEN, 1999 (4 folders) (Box 32)
  - Lindsey Collen (Box 33)
  - Network of East-West Women (Box 33)
  - 5 Witches, 1992-1993 (3 folders) (Box 33)
  - Bosnia and Croatia, 1992-1993 (2 folders) (Box 33)
  - UN Human Rights Report (Box 33)
  - Bosnia Herzegovina - War and Rape Camps (Box 34)
  - Women for Women in Bosnia (Box 34)
  - Strategies, Training, and Advocacy for Reconciliation (STAR) (Box 34)
  - The Five Croatian 'Witches' (Box 34)
  - Dubravka Ugaresic (Box 34)
  - Alenka Puhar (Box 34)
  - Czech Gender Studies (Box 34)
  - Carmen-Francesca Banciu (Box 34)
  - Ex-Yugo PEN (Box 34)
  - Living in a Le Carre Novel by Slavenka Drakulic (Box 34)
  - Rada Ivekovi (Box 34)
  - Diana Guli (Box 34)
  - Nawal El Saadawi (Box 35)
  - Israeli PEN (Box 35)
  - Cyprus (Box 35)
  - SOS (French coalition re: Islam fund) (Box 35)
  - Alipoor Khazei (Box 35)
  - Shafika (Box 35)
  - Arab Women - Lists and Biblio. Info (Box 35)
  - Clippings (Box 35)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous PEN (Box 35)
  - Frankfurt Reports, 1994 (2 folders) (Box 35)
  - Karin Clark (Box 35)
  - Ana Luise Valdes (Box 35)
  - International PEN (Box 35)
  - Resumes re: Frankfurt (Box 36)
  - Frankfurt Book Fair (Box 36)
  - Frankfurt Project (Box 36)
  - IPWWC accounts, 1993-1994 (2 folders) (Box 36)
  - Budgets and notes for budgets (Box 36)
  - Jenny McKean Moore Fund for Writers (Box 36)
  - Overall budgetary notes, records, memos, estimates (Box 36)
  - Contributions, 1992-1993 (Box 36)
  - Fundraising ideas - projects, notes (Box 36)
  - IPWWC board and chair (Box 36)
  - IPWWC accounts, 1992 (Box 36)
  - Lindsey Collen (Box 37)
  - Koumanthio Diallo (Box 37)
  - Flora Nwapa (Box 37)
  - Firdous Azim (Box 37)
  - Hong Kong PEN (Box 37)
  - Nguyen Thi Thoi (Box 37)
  - Eva Molcadskyte (Box 37)
  - International PEN (7 folders) (Box 37)
  - Barbara Chase-Riboud (Box 38)
  - PEN Correspondence - Europe (Box 38)
  - Peter Day (Box 38)
  - Aline Petterson (Box 38)
  - Maria Elena Cruz Varela (Box 38)
  - Mirta Yáñez (Box 38)
  - Maria Arrillaga (Box 38)
  - International PEN(2 folders) (Box 38)
  - International Network of Women Writers (Box 39)
  - Organizing meeting for International Network of Women Writers, 1989 (Box 39)
  - International Women's Committee PEN, Toronto/Montreal Congress (Box 39)
  - International PEN Peace Committee, 1989 (Box 39)
  - PEN International Congress, Toronto/Montreal, 1989 (Box 39)
  - 54th World Congress, 1989 (2 folders) (Box 39)
  - Meredith/Congress File (Box 39)
  - International PEN (Box 39)
  - 56th World Congress List of Participants, 1991 (Box 40)
  - Women's Committee Meetings, Vienna Congress, 1991 (Box 40)
  - Vienna Minutes/List, 1991 (Box 40)
  - Women's Committee Minutes, 56th Congress, Vienna, 1991 (Box 40)
  - 56th World Congress, 1991 (Box 40)
  - Palestinian Center, 1991- (Box 40)
  - Sisterhood is Global Conference (Box 40)
  - International PEN(3 folders) (Box 40)
  - Writers in Prison Committee Newsletter (Box 41)
  - Marlyn Tadros Human Rights/Women's Rights Cairo (Box 41)
  - Fatou Ndiaye Sow (Box 41)
  - Lucina Kathman (Box 41)
  - Alison Spedding (Box 41)
  - Alicia Partnoy (Box 41)
  - Helene Kafi (Box 41)
  - Keiko Ochiai (Box 41)
  - Asian Misc. Correspondence (Box 41)
  - Greta Rana (Box 41)
  - Clippings (Box 41)
  - International PEN (Box 41)
  - INT PEN-IPWWC, 2005 (Box 42)
  - PEN Moscow Congress grant proposal Rockefeller, 2000 (Box 42)
  - PEN International Committee, 2001 (Box 42)
  - International PEN Centers list, 2000 (Box 42)
  - IPWWC Lucina (Box 42)
  - Canadian PEN (Toronto) (Box 42)
  - Elena Potiguara (Grumin) (Box 42)
  - Aïcha Lemsine (2 folders) (Box 42)
  - Budget, 1992-1993 (Box 43)
  - Women's Committee budget (Box 43)
  - Fundraising mailing, 1992 (Box 43)
  - Kerry Kennedy Cuomo/Nan Richardson (Box 43)
  - Proposals - Women's presses in South (Box 43)
  - Possible Fnds Notes (Box 43)
  - Not now try later, 1993 (Box 43)
  - Partners (Box 43)
  - Gender based censorship (Box 43)
  - UN Literacy Day, 1994 (Box 43)
  - Fundraising Mailing, 1993 (Box 43)
  - Women Writer's Committee, Rio de Janeiro, 1992 (Box 44)
  - Writers in Prison Committee (Box 44)
  - Correspondence with International PEN (Box 44)
  - International PEN (4 folders) (Box 44)
  - International PEN post-Congress, 1997 (Box 44)
  - Revision to International PEN Bylaws, 1997 (Box 44)
  - Constitution of International PEN (Box 44)
  - IPWWC, 1997 (Box 44)
  - List of centers and officers (Box 45)
  - Ex-Yugo PEN (Box 45)
  - Dubrovnik Congress, 1993 (Box 45)
  - 62nd World Congress Registration Booklet, 1995 (Box 45)
  - Int. PEN and UNESCO, 1997 (Box 45)
  - Int. PEN Candidates for Pres., 1997 (Box 45)
  - Important IPWWC papers, correspondence, 1997 (Box 45)
  - Int. PEN Secretariat, 1996-1997 (Box 45)
  - Board meeting Antwerp logistics, 1997 (Box 45)
  - Edinburgh PEN Congress 1997 (Box 45)
  - Int. PEN corres., notes, memos, 1997 (Box 45)
  - PEN International (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - International PEN, 1997 (8 folders) (Box 46)
  - Kate Burke (Box 46)
  - Homero Aridjis (Box 46)
  - PEN Congress, 1997 (Box 46)
  - PEN International, 1998 (6 folders) (Box 47)
  - Freedom to Write Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 47)
  - Writers in Exile Program (Box 47)
  - List of centers and offices, 1998 (Box 47)
  - Terry endorsement letters, 1998 (Box 47)
  - PEN dynamite (Box 47)
  - Inna Tchckalova (2 folders) (Box 48)
  - 5th International Feminist Book Fair, 1992 (2 folders) (Box 48)
  - 57th PEN Congress, 1992 (Box 48)
  - Minutes of the meeting of the assembly of delegates of International PEN, 1997 (Box 48)
  - International PEN (Box 48)
  - Writers in Prison Committee (Box 49)
  - WWC Santiago Congress (Box 49)
  - PEN Congress Prague, 1994 (2 folders) (Box 49)
  - Women's Committee, International PEN Congress, 1992 (Box 49)
  - PEN Congress, Barcelona, 1992 (Box 49)
  - Barcelona Congress, Writers in Prison (Box 49)
  - International PEN (Box 49)
  - Susan Davis WEDO (Box 50)
  - Other international Women's Networks (Box 50)
  - Campaign for Peace and Democracy (Box 50)
  - Notebooks, 1993-1994 (Box 50)
  - International PEN (Box 50)
  - Santiago De Compostela (Box 51)
  - Barcelona In Session Resolution (Box 51)
  - International PEN Congress, 1993 (Box 51)
  - Libuse Ludovika (Box 51)
  - Prague (Box 51)
  - International PEN Congress, Rio de Janeiro, 1992 (Box 51)
  - International PEN Congress, Santiago de Compostela, 1993 (Box 51)
  - Writers in Prison Committee (Box 51)
  - Correspondence (Box 51)
  - International Feminist Book Fair (Box 51)
  - CETLALIC - The Tlahuica Center for Language and Cultural Exchange, Cuernavaca, Morelos, Mexico (Box 51)
  - Press IPWC (Box 51)
  - Int. PEN-IPWWC 2006 (Box 51)
  - International PEN (Box 51)
  - Taslima Nasrin, 1994 (2 folders) (Box 52)
  - Basic Taslima Packet - Press (Box 52)
  - IPWWC Press (Taslima and me) (Box 52)
  - Taslima Poems - Writings (Box 52)
  - TN US Visa, 1995-6 (Box 52)
  - Taslima Clips, 2nd Stage (Box 52)
  - Taslima Nasrin (2 folders) (Box 53)
  - Taslima Nasrin, correspondence and notes, 1994 (Box 53)
  - Taslima Nasrin Stage 1, Correspondence, 1993 (Box 53)
  - Taslima re: US Trip (Box 53)
  - Taslima Nasrin, 1995 (3 folders) (Box 54)
  - Taslima Nasrin, human rights and government documents, 1994 (Box 54)
  - Taslima clips (Box 54)
  - Taslima Nasrin, Stage 2, correspondence and notes, 1994 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence (Box 55)
  - Media and Democracy Conference, 1996 (2 folders) (Box 55)
  - Fatow, 1997 (Box 55)
  - Latin America Misc. Correspondence (Box 55)
  - Kazuko Watanabe (Box 55)
  - Ketaki Kushari Dyson (Box 55)
  - Ketaki (Box 55)
  - Grant letters, 1998-1999 (Box 55)
  - Beijing Finances, 1995 (Box 55)
  - Mariella's Air France problem, 2001 (Box 55)
  - Women's WORLD Board meeting, 2006 (Box 56)
  - Ms. Foundation Indian Travel Grant, 2006 (Box 56)
  - Lydia Cacho, 2006 (Box 56)
  - Women's WORLD India Colloquium, 2007 (Box 56)
  - Women Center Stage, 2007 (Box 56)
  - Expenses India Travel, 2007 (Box 56)
  - Women's WORLD Financials, 2007-2008 (2 folders) (Box 56)
  - Appeal, 2007 (Box 56)
  - Saroop Dhruv (Box 56)
  - Funding packet for proposal (Box 57)
  - Feminist Press 2007 (Box 57)
  - CUNY Graduate Center 2000 (Box 57)
  - International PEN (5 folders) (Box 57)
  - Japan (Box 58)
  - Mailing lists (4 folders) (Box 58)
  - Hanifa Deen On Taslima (Box 58)
  - Asmita (Box 59)
  - S. Asian workshop plan (Box 59)
  - Gender and Censorship Report, 2000 (Box 59)
  - Gender and Censorship Project (Box 59)
  - India National Colloquium, 2001 (Box 59)
  - India proposal, 2002 (Box 59)
  - Indian project final doc draft, 2002 (Box 59)
  - Writings by Ketaki Kushari Dyson (Box 59)
  - Fahmida Riaz 1997-2001 (3 folders) (Box 59)
  - Shamim Sikder (Box 59)
  - Mridula Garg (Box 59)
  - India (Box 59)
  - International PEN (Box 59)
  - India (Box 60)
  - Taslima Nasrin, 1999 (Box 60)
  - Women's Vision - A Culture of Peace Seminar, New Delhi, 1999 (Box 60)
  - Taslima Nasrin, 1997 (Box 60)
  - Taslima Washington Post, 1998 (Box 60)